<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<title>Tuximail</title>
<description>A Linux Blog with irregular updates</description>
<link>https://tuximail.github.io</link>
<language>en-us</language>
<pubDate>Fri 21 Jun 2019 10:51:52 PM CEST</pubDate>
<item>
		<title>Send Mail for every SSH Login</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Send Mail for every SSH Login</h1>

<p>If you&rsquo;re googling this topic there is an unbelievable amount of grossly negligent &ldquo;solutions&rdquo; to this problem.</p>

<p>The top two results in my search engine tell you to do this:</p>

<p><code>$ cd /root<br />
$ vi .bashrc</code></p>

<p>And trigger some mail there with the information wanted.
This is insecure for multiple reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li>One can login via SSH without triggering the <i>.bashrc</i> file. For example with <code>ssh -N</code></li>
<li>This is the most important part: You should never ever enable direct ssh login for root! The fact that those tutorials are encouraging such behaviour is sick</li>
<li>Every authentication should only and only be managed by <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180303034326/http://www.tuxradar.com/content/how-pam-works">PAM</a></li>
</ol>


<p>This is the reason why I have the following setup I hereby share with you:</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tuximail/scripts/blob/master/login_notify.sh">This script</a> (placed somewhere in your system) is used to send a mail after a login. To trigger it, PAM has to be told so in <em>/etc/pam.d/sshd</em>:</p>

<p><code>session optional pam_exec.so seteuid /etc/ssh/login_notify.sh</code></p>

<p>The second word <em>optional</em> is important here as it allows a login even if the script doesn&rsquo;t exit with code 0. If you replace it with <em>required</em> the login will fail if the script fails. This might not be what you want because the mail sending process may be broken because some issues your server might have and this will prevent you from logging in.
Don&rsquo;t forget to make the script itself executable:</p>

<p><code>chmod +x /path/to/login_notify.sh</code></p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/pam.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>pam.html</guid>
		<pubDate>06/19 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>Setup Netflix in Kodi for Raspberrypi 3</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Setup Netflix in Kodi for Raspberrypi 3</h1>


<p>This is a short instruction on how to get the <a href="https://github.com/asciidisco/plugin.video.netflix">Netflix Plugin for Kodi</a> working on a raspberrypi 3 with the current Beta Version 0.14.22. It may be outdated when you read it. Especially have a look <a href="https://github.com/caphm/kodi-repo/raw/master/repository.kodi-repo-caphm/repository.kodi-repo-caphm-1.0.0.zip">at the official testing repo</a> for a currently working version.</p>



<p>First of all you need the inputstream adaptive Plugin installed on your raspberrypi: <code>sudo apt-get install kodi-inputstream-adaptive</code></p>



<p>The plugin also calls for a python module called cryptodome so install it via <code>pip install --user pycryptodomex</code> for the user you start kodi with. Beware: If you&#8217;re using multiple python versions at once, ensure youre installing it with the correct pip (same version as your kodi uses).</p>



<p>No we need the widevine library which decrypts the DRM protected netflix streams. The easiest way of getting it is to install the Widevine Support Plugin as described <a href="https://www.matthuisman.nz/2018/05/kodi-widevine-support.html">here</a>. This will automatically download the version suitable for your architecture and also plays a DRM protected Stream as test.</p>



<p>No you can install the netflix plugin. For me only the current Beta Version (<a href="https://m.mediafire.com/folder/tnu4623j66c66">direct donwloads</a>) worked. After installing it you can login to netflix and stream a video. The plugin then will upgrade your widevine version from above which will need 2 GB free space on your system during installation (it extracts the library from a chrome OS installation image) and root privilieges which you can grant trhough the installation process.</p>



<p>After this you should be able to watch videos from netflix. However you remain with one issue: Your raspberrypi is not capable of decrypting and watching a 1080p stream simultaneously. So you have to make 720p as default. To do so go to the Settings of your netflix addon > Inputstream Addon Settings > Set both &#8222;max resolution&#8220; values to &#8222;720p&#8220;.</p>



<p><strong>Known errors</strong><br>I experienced some trouble logging into my account and playing a video. For both problems I found an entry in my log file (~/.kodi/temp/kodi.log) which looks like: <code>route(filter(None, g.PATH.split('/')))</code> The solution here is to switch your netflix Settings to IPC over HTTP: Settings &gt; Expert &gt; Enable IPC over HTTP. I had to play around with it a bit to make it work so don&#8217;t hassitate to turn it on and off at least once and try the failed action in between.<br><br></p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/netflix.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>netflix.html</guid>
		<pubDate>03/19 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>How to be a responsible web developer/web admin</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>How to be a responsible web developer/web admin</h1>

<p>Due to the latest changes in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GDPR</a> I stumbled upon some topics and issues people where facing while trying to make their website compliant to the new demands. This brought me to this little tutorial on how to make your website more secure and less sniffing.<br />
Not all of the topics will be GDPR-related as this is NOT another &#8222;how to make your website GDPR compliant&#8220;-article. However this is a collection of different things you, as a web Developer or Administrator of for example a wordpress site should be aware of. Basically it&#8217;s a &#8222;How to not fuck around with the security of your users&#8220;.</p>
<h3>Google Fonts</h3>
<p>A lot of People use &#8222;<a href="https://fonts.google.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Google Fonts</a>&#8220; in their website. So do the most wordpress themes. This is not a bad idead by default. The problem is that you cannot be sure every user has the Font you are using installed. So if you use Arial as a default Font and someone doesn&#8217;t have this font installed on his computer &#8211; no text can be displayed. This is not exactly right, because every web browser provides a default Font it falls back to in such cases. So the website is just not displayed with the Font you would want it to, but with a Fallback-Font. To ensure everyone can see it with the same Font you can use Google Fonts where the Fonts are loaded directly from Google.</p>
<p><strong>The Problem:</strong> With every visit the IP Adress of the user gets transported to Google. So in fact they can track every user uniquely over every site where Google Fonts are used. This is bad and you shouldn&#8217;t be part of that problem. </p>
<p><strong>The Solution:</strong> If you are a web Developer please consider providing the Font as a TTF File as described <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/cssref/css3_pr_font-face_rule.asp" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.<br />
If you use wordpress, Google Fonts are very likely to be used by your theme. To verfiy this, you can run the following Linux Command in your wordpress root Folder:</p>
<p><code>grep -ir "fonts.googleapis" .</code></p>
<p>If you get any results Google Fonts are used by one of your themes. The normal way to load them under wordpress is via the following PHP function:</p>
<p><code>wp_enqueue_style( 'Gfonts', 'https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Alegreya+Sans:300,regular,italic,500,700|Roboto:300,300italic,regular,italic,500,700', array(), true );</code></p>
<p>The values may differ in your case but the URL for Google Fonts is the important part. To disable this function just put a # before this specific line in every PHP file found by the grep command above. You can ensure you did this for every line by running</p>
<p><code>grep -ir "fonts.googleapis" . | grep -iv "#"</code></p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t get any result you sucessfully removed Google Fonts from your website. Please remember to have a look on your website if it still looks good.</p>
<h3>Referrer-Policy</h3>
<p>When you click a link, your browser will typically send the HTTP referer header to the webserver where the destination webpage is at. The header contains the full URL of the page you came from. This lets sites see where traffic comes from. The header is also sent when external resources (such as images, fonts, JS and CSS) are loaded.</p>
<p><strong>The Problem:</strong> if you link to an external site, this site can track the movement of your users as soon as they visit another page which links to them. In combination with cookies this is one of the most useful tracking possibilities out there. In fact you should not imagine the scenario as the tracking by one single page but by a tracking network consisting of hundreds of thousands of pages where it is really likely that one of the other websites of such a network will be called by the same user. Also think of facebook buttons on a website. As soon as a logged in facebook user visits a site with a facebook button (which, by it&#8217;s nature, refers to facebook), facebook knows that you visited this exact page.</p>
<p><strong>The Solution:</strong> A great invention called &#8222;<a href="https://w3c.github.io/webappsec-referrer-policy/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Referrer Policy</a>&#8220; gives you the posibilitie to prevent the transfer of such data to other sites. This is not just for clicked links but also for other referres such as linked images, etc.<br />
You should have a look at <a href="https://w3c.github.io/webappsec-referrer-policy/#referrer-policies" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the different policies</a>. However I recommend to use <code>no-referrer</code> which disables the referrer Header completly. To do so add the following meta tag to the <code>header.php</code> of your wordpress theme or your normal HTML Header:</p>
<p><code>&lt;meta name='referrer' content='no-referrer'&gt;</code></p>
<p>Also you can use <a href="https://anders.unix.se/2015/05/15/wordpress-plugin-noreferrer/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">this</a> wordpress plugin.</p>
<h3>HTTP Headers</h3>
<p>This part focuses on the security of your website. We want to prevent XSS, MIME-sniffing of the content type and framing of the website. We use the following Header options for this purpose:</p>
<p><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/HTTP_strict_transport_security" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Strict-Transport-Security</a><br />
<a href="https://htaccess.wordpress.com/2009/09/22/x-content-type-options-nosniff-header/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">X-Content-Type-Options</a><br />
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/X-Frame-Options" rel="noopener" target="_blank">X-Frame-Options</a><br />
<a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ieinternals/2011/01/31/controlling-the-xss-filter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">X-XSS-Protection</a></p>
<p>Here is a complete <code>.htaccess</code> file with all the Headers set:</p>
<p><code><IfModule mod_headers.c><br />
	Header set X-XSS-Protection "1; mode=block"<br />
	Header always append X-Frame-Options SAMEORIGIN<br />
	Header set X-Content-Type-Options nosniff<br />
        Header set Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=15768000<br />
</IfModule></code></p>
<p>Just place the <code>.htaccess</code> File in your webroot or appent the code above into any existing <code>.htaccess</code> File. Please note that you need to enable the apache module <code>mod_headers</code> to make this work.<br />
You can ensure the changes worked via curl:</p>
<p><code>$ curl -I <em>URL</em><br />
HTTP/1.1 200 OK<br />
Date: Thu, 24 May 2018 19:05:14 GMT<br />
Server: Apache/2.2.15 (CentOS)<br />
X-Powered-By: PHP/7.2.0<br />
X-Robots-Tag: noindex<br />
<strong>X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff</strong><br />
Access-Control-Expose-Headers: X-WP-Total, X-WP-TotalPages<br />
Access-Control-Allow-Headers: Authorization, Content-Type<br />
Allow: GET<br />
<strong>Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=15768000</strong><br />
<strong>X-Frame-Options: DENY</strong><br />
<strong>X-Xss-Protection: 1; mode=block</strong><br />
Connection: close<br />
Content-Type: application/json; charset=UTF-8<br />
</code></p>
<h3>SSL</h3>
<p>I shouldn&#8217;t need to say much about SSL and the need of an encrypted website. Since <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">letsencrypt</a> launched you have no excuse for not having a valid SSL Certificate. What you should do is to enforce the use of https even if someone acesses the website unencrypted. This can be done in the .htaccess file:</p>
<p><code>RewriteEngine on<br />
RewriteCond %{HTTPS} !=on<br />
RewriteCond %{ENV:HTTPS} !=on<br />
RewriteRule .* https://%{SERVER_NAME}%{REQUEST_URI} [R=301,L]</code></p>
<p>While doing this you also should ensure that you&#8217;re only linking to sources such as images, etc. via https.</p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/websec.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>websec.html</guid>
		<pubDate>05/18 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>Run configure.ac File</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Run configure.ac File</h1>

<p>Just a short note for everyone who&#8217;s expecting a <code>configure</code> file in a Software he wants to build but there&#8217;s only a <code>configure.ac</code> file. This File is for the so called <code>autoconf</code> command which generates the configure file. Just run <code>autoconf</code> to generate it.</p>
<p>Please mind that you need to install the following packages for sucess:</p>
<p>autogen<br />
autoconf<br />
libtool<br />
autoconf</p>
<p>If you miss one of those packages you might end up with the following error: <code>configure.ac:3: error: possibly undefined macro</code></p>
<p>Sometimes you need to install some dependencies for the configure process. To do so run <code>autoreconf --install</code></p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/configure.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>configure.html</guid>
		<pubDate>05/18 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>Reset password for wordpress installation</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Reset password for wordpress installation</h1>

If you ever in the position of having forgotten your password for a user of your wordpress installation here are good news: You can reset it.<br />
Connect to your mysql database as root and execute:<br />
<br /><code>update wp_users set user_pass=md5("password") where user_login="user";</code><br/><br />
User <i>user</i> now authenticates with password <i>password</i>. You can now login with those credentials and change your password in the wordpress dashboard.<br /><br />
If you want to set your password directly via sql ensure you have disabled history logging (e.g. via <code>export MYSQL_HISTFILE=/dev/null</code>) otherwise one would be able to read your password in cleartext from the historyfile <code>~/.mysql_history</code>. Don't forget to set MYSQL_HISTFILE back to normal.]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/wordpressrecov.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>wordpressrecov.html</guid>
		<pubDate>01/15 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>Explain parts of a linux command with explainshell</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Explain parts of a linux command with explainshell</h1>

<p>Ever had a linux command and not sure what it does exactly?
<a href="https://explainshell.com/">explainshell.com</a> is here to help you! Enter the command in the search field and the site will disassemble it into its parts and explain what every part does. You should do this everytime before you just blindly copy and paste something from the internet.</p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/explainshell.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>explainshell.html</guid>
		<pubDate>01/14 </pubDate>
	</item>
<item>
		<title>Two Problems</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<h1>Two problems</h1>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use regular expressions.&rdquo; Now they have two problems.</p>

<p>Some people, when faced with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use binary.&rdquo; Now they have 10 problems.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use threads,&rdquo; and then two they hav erpoblesms.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think &ldquo;I know, I’ll use multithreading&rdquo;. Nothhw tpe yawrve o oblems.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use mutexes.&rdquo; Now they have</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think: &ldquo;I know, I’ll use caching.&rdquo; Now they have one problems.</p>

<p>Some people see a problem and think &ldquo;I know, I’ll use Java!&rdquo; Now they have a ProblemFactory.</p>

<p>Some programmers, when confronted with a problem, think &ldquo;I know, I’ll use floating point arithmetic.&rdquo; Now they have 1.999999999997 problems.</p>

<p>Some people, wanting an escape from their full-time job, think &ldquo;I know, I’ll contribute to open source.&rdquo; Now they have two full-time jobs.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think: &ldquo;I know, I’ll think outside the box!&rdquo; Now, they have 3.75 problems, an entirely new framework, and three dozen toll house cookies cooling in the kitchen.</p>

<p>Some people when confronted with a desire to use pithy quotes in their presentations think &ldquo;I know, I’ll use something from Star Wars&rdquo;. Now two problems they have.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use UTF8&rdquo; Now they à??????µ?ç°§ùÔ_¦Ñ?.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I’ll use PHP!&rdquo; Now they have (&ldquo;1 apple&rdquo; + &ldquo;1 orange&rdquo;) problems.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I’ll use Perl!&rdquo; Now they have more than one way to have more than one problem….</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use Shareware.&rdquo; Now they have two trials.</p>

<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think, &ldquo;I know, I’ll use delegations.&rdquo; Now their problem is a problem of their problem.</p>

<p>Some people when confronted with a problem think &ldquo;I know, I’ll quote jwz&rdquo;. Now everyone has a problem.</p>

<p><a href="http://nedbatchelder.com/blog/201204/two_problems.html">Source</a></p>]]></description>
		<link>https://tuximail.github.io/twoproblems.html</link>
		<guid isPermalink=false>twoproblems.html</guid>
		<pubDate>10/12 </pubDate>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
